Ahmed Karam Elswelky

Frontend Developer, ITI Graduate, Siemens Software Diploma Graduate

ahmed.karam.elswelky@gmail.com (+20) 102-558-6763 in LinkedIn G Github My Portfolio

Summary

I am a frontend developer with **over 1 year of experience** in frontend development, specializing in building responsive, high-performing applications. A graduate of ITI and Siemens Software Academy, I excel in agile teamwork, delivering optimized solutions, and enhancing user experiences. Skilled in Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, SCSS, and CMS platforms like TYPO3 and WordPress, I stay updated with the latest web development trends and best practices.

Education		
07/2024 – 12/2024	Siemens Software Academy Diploma, Siemens Software Academy ☑ Effective coding practices, algorithms, data structures, and problemsolving. Web development techniques and tools.	Cairo, Egypt
11/2022 - 03/2023	Information Technology Institute (ITI), Front-end web development and Cross-Platform Mobile Applications. The Certificate Link ☑	
06/2017 – 06/2022	Faculty of petroleum and mining engineering, Suez Univ., Bachelor's in Refining and Petrochemical Engineering	

Professional Experience

10/2023 – present	Frontend Developer, Ai. Parse ☑ Developing and maintaining web applications using TYPO3, JavaScript, and Angular. Implementing responsive and user-friendly interfaces. Collaborating with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software solutions. Enhancing application performance and optimizing code for scalability.	
07/2023 – 01/2024	Software Developer, <i>Medgulf Insurance Company</i> ☑ Developing new websites with Progress 4Gl .	
03/2023 - 07/2023	Freelancer Working on freelancing project using the technologies I learnt	

Skills

Scripts & Programming Languages

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript (ES6+), and TypeScript

Soft skills

- Agile methodology, leadership, time management, continuous learning, communication, presentation skills, problem-solving, teamwork, strong individual contributor, and adaptability.

Libraries & Frameworks

- Angular, Bootstrap, Bulma, jQuery

Version Controls:

- GIT

Projects

Portfolio | Angular+17 🛮

- **Description:** A professional website showcasing projects, skills, and achievements. Built with Angular and TypeScript, it features a clean design, responsive layout, and intuitive navigation.
- **Key Features:** Angular 17+, standalone components, dark/light modes, animations, routing, responsive design.
- **Skills:** Angular, TypeScript, Bootstrap Material Design, Toastr, Animations, Responsive Design, Figma.

Travel Everywhere | Angular 🛮

- **Description:** An Angular app for exploring and booking flights with advanced filtering, dynamic flight cards, and a user-friendly home page.
- **Key Features:** Flight search, filters, dynamic flight cards, routing, animations, responsive design.
- **Skills:** Angular, TypeScript, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Responsive Design.

Angular Note App 🛮

- **Description:** An Angular app for creating, editing, and deleting notes with unique identifiers for efficient management.
- **Key Features:** CRUD operations, sorting, filtering, routing, notifications, styling, animations, responsive design.
- Skills: Angular, TypeScript, SCSS, Bulma, HTML5, CSS3, Toastr, Responsive Design, Lazy Loading.

Eshraq Alazhar Academy, ITI Graduation Project ☑

- **Description:** This is an Islamic academy for teaching Quran for non-Arab students.
- My Role: Team Leader & Developer
- Skills: React, Node.js, Mongo DB, Bootstrap, JS, HTML5 and CSS3

Angular Book Shop 🛮

- **Description:** This is a website for downloading and buying Islamic books.
- Skills: Angular, Node.js, Mongo DB, TypeScript, Bootstrap, JS, HTML5 and CSS3

Extra Curriculum Actitvities

08/2021 - present

TareequlJannah Institute and Harf Institute, *Islamic Education Tutor*

Languages

English language proficiency due to my close interaction with many European and American students.

EnglishHighly proficient in speaking and writing
Native